<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
    <Title>Alm Lab Software: ANGST</Title>

    <contentPane>

    </contentPane>

    <rightPane>

    </rightPane>
    <midPane>
    <br/>
    <h4>ANGST </h4>
    <h5>the ANalyzer of Gene and Species Trees. </h5>

    <div id="software">
    by Lawrence David and Eric Alm <br/>
    <img class="floatRight" src="img/29_AnGST.png" alt="ANGST"/>
    </div>
    <div id="softwareMed">
    UPDATE<br/>
    Run AnGST online using the <a href="http://almlab.mit.edu/angst">AnGST online server</a>. Simply upload your tree
    files and processing takes place on our servers. Does not require code
    downloading or prior programming knowledge!<p/>

    Several algorithmic approaches for the inference of prokaryotic gene family
    evolutionary histories have been proposed. Although divergent in their
    backgrounds, these algorithms are united by a common goal: the proposal of a
    series of horizontal gene transfer (HGT), gene duplication (DUP) and gene
    loss (LOS) events to explain observed distributions of orthologous genes
    amongst extant prokaryotic genomes. Regrettably, these inference algorithms
    also all share at least one of the following shortcomings: 1) an inability
    to model both HGT and DUP simultaneously; 2) an inability to incorporate
    ortholog phylogenetic information; 3) a lack of robustness to phylogenetic
    construction errors. We avoid all three of these limitations in a novel
    algorithm that we have developed, entitled the Analyzer of Gene and Species
    Trees (AnGST). In brief, AnGST performs a phylogenetic reconciliation
    between a given species and gene tree, positing the best scoring set of HGT,
    DUP, and LOS events to explain all topological incongruities between the two
    trees. In order to protect against phylogenetic noise, we have designed
    AnGST to be capable of incorporating information from dozens of bootstrap
    trees simultaneously. In cases of variations among bootstrap subtrees, the
    subtree that best accords with the reference tree is adopted. <p/>

    References <br/>
    <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21170026">(1) Lawrence A. David and Eric J. Alm. “Rapid evolutionary innovation during
    an Archean Genetic Expansion.” Nature, Vol. 469, No. 7328. (6 January 2011),
    pp. 93-96. </a>
    <br/><br/>
    Data <br/>
    <a href="angst/files/angst.data.tar.gz">Download AnGST Data</a><br/>

    </div>

    </midPane>
    <footer>

    </footer>
</Document>




