<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
    <!-- replace the contents in the brackets, erase the brackets themselves-->
    <Title>Alm Lab Member: Francisco Camas</Title>

    <contentPane>
    <h3>Francisco Camas</h3>
        <div id="member">
        <img class="floatRight" src="img/Francisco_Camas.jpg" width="200" alt="image 1"/> <!--must store the image file in img folder-->
        <h4>Research Interests</h4>
	I'm a physicist and systems biologist currently working on the characterization of phage/host regulatory interactions and amino-acid/nucleotide recognition codes. I'm also considering evolutionary scenarios for microbiome assembly and developing methods to make more selective metagenomics, in which all the sequencing effort could be directed to map the diversity of particular phage families.
	<p/>
	<h4>Past Life</h4>
	I received my Ph.D. in Physical Sciences for a multi-scale work within the subfield of Systems Biology concerning the network motifs, the basic building blocks of transcriptional networks in bacteria. My work, that was supervised by prof. Juan Poyatos and prof. Jesus Blazquez, combined experimental microbiology genetics (the redesign of small genetic circuits in vivo) with bioinformatics and mathematical modelling. My Ph. D. thesis (in Spanish) can be found <a href="http://eprints.ucm.es/10460/" target="_blank">here</a>.
	<p/>
	<h4>Science and Music</h4>
	Before becoming a scientist I was a professional musician and worked as a professor in several music conservatories. My scientific and musical projects, as well as my incursions into the intermediate field located between these disciplines can be found at my <a href="http://www.franciscocamas.com" target="_blank">personal web page</a>.
	<p/>
	<h4>Selected Publications</h4>
	Camas FM, Alm EJ and Poyatos JF (2010). Local gene regulation details a recognition code within the LacI transcriptional factor family. PLoS Computational Biology, 6, 11, e1000989 [<a href="http://www.ploscompbiol.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pcbi.1000989" target="_blank">Link</a>]
	<p/>
	Camas FM and Poyatos JF (2008). What determines the assembly of transcriptional network motifs in Escherichia coli? PLoS ONE, 3, 11, e3657 [<a href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info:doi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0003657" target="_blank">Link</a>]
	<p/>
	Camas FM, Blázquez J and Poyatos, JF (2006). Autogenous and nonautogenous control of response in a genetic network. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (PNAS), 103, 12718 [<a href="http://www.pnas.org/content/103/34/12718.full" target="_blank">Link</a>]
	<p/>
        <p/>

    </div>
    </contentPane>

    <rightPane>
        <br/>
        <div id="memberDir">

        <h4>Francisco Camas </h4>
	Postdoctoral Associate<br/>
        Alm Laboratory<br/>
        fmcamas@mit.edu<br/>
        <p/>

        <h4>Education</h4>
	Ph.D. Physical Sciences, Universidad Complutense de Madrid.
	<p>
	B.S. Theoretical Physics, Universidad Autonoma de Madrid.
	</p>
	Diploma of Higher Teacher of Music, Malaga Higher Conservatoire of Music.
        <p/>

        </div>

    </rightPane>
    <midPane>

    </midPane>
    <footer>
        <hr />
        <!--Evolutionary, Ecological and Environmental Systems Biology-->
        <img src="img/bar1.png" alt="bar1"/>
    </footer>
</Document>
