<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
    <Title>Alm Lab Member: Mathilde Poyet </Title>

    <contentPane>
    <h3>Mathilde Poyet</h3>
        <div id="member">
            <!-- rename the image file here. jpgs, pngs, whatever are fine. -->
        <img class="floatRight" src="img/mathilde_poyet2.jpg" width="150" alt="Mathilde Poyet 2"/>
        <h4>Research Interests</h4>
        I am an ecologist with a special interest in biological communities. During my
        PhD, I characterized the invasion processes of an insect (<i>Drosophila suzukii</i>)
        and its impact on the invaded communities at different levels of organization.
        Now, I keep on studying community and ecosystem stability with a particular
        focus on the bacterial communities (microbiota) living in and on animals.
        <p/>

		<h4>Current projects</h4>
        So far, the great majority of gut microbes have not been cultured in
        laboratory. My project aims at building comprehensive libraries of pure culture
        covering the breadth of bacterial strains contained within several human guts.
        Using recreated complex communities from my libraries, I will test different
        hypotheses on the structure, stability, resilience and resistance of gut
        communities.
        <p/>

            <h4>Global Microbiome Conservancy</h4>
        I am also one of the co-founders of The Global Microbiome Conservancy, a non-profit collaboration between scientists and communities around the world, unified around a common goal: to collect and preserve the full biodiversity of human gut microbes for future generations. Learn more on our <a href="http://microbiomeconservancy.org/">website</a>.<p/>

            <!-- rename the image file here. jpgs, pngs, whatever are fine. -->
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/mathilde_poyet3.jpg" width="150" alt="Mathilde Poyet 3"/>
        <p/>
    </div>
    </contentPane>

    <rightPane>
        <br/>
        <div id="memberDir">
        <h4>Mathilde Poyet</h4>
        Postdoctoral Associate<br/>
        mpoyet at mit dot edu<br/>
        <li>My <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Mathilde_Poyet">Researchgate</a> profile.</li><br/>
        <p/>

        <h4>Education</h4>
        <ul>
        <li>Ph.D., Community Ecology and Biological invasions, University of Lyon 1, France  <a href="http://lbbe.univ-lyon1.fr/?lang=en">Biometrie and Evolutionary Biology Laboratory</a>. 2014.</li>
        <li>B.S., Ecosystems, <a href="https://www.u-picardie.fr/university-of-picardy-jules-verne-110990.kjsp">Picardie - Jules Verne University, France</a>. 2011.</li>
        </ul>
        <p/>
        <img class="floatRight" src="img/mathilde_poyet4.jpg" width="150" alt="Mathilde Poyet 4"/>
        </div>
    </rightPane>
        <!-- Don't change anything below here! -->
    <midPane>
    </midPane>
    <footer>
        <hr />
        <img src="img/bar1.png" alt="bar1"/>
    </footer>
</Document>
