<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
    <Title>Alm Lab Members</Title>

    <contentPane>
        <h3>Lab Members</h3>
    <h4>PI: Eric Alm</h4>
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatRight" src="img/ericAlm.png" width="150" alt="ericAlm"/>
        The human microbiome plays a key role in human health and disease.
        Research in my group includes both computational/theoretical
        and experimental approaches to understanding and engineering the human microbiome.
        Our research is focused on translating basic science discoveries rapidly into the clinic, where they can contribute to better outcomes for patients.
        Some areas of special interest include:
        <ul class="square">
        <li>Developing therapeutics based on synthetic microbial communities</li>
        <li>Personalized medicine</li>
        <li>Monitoring human activities through Smart Sewers</li>
        <li>Smart Toilets that track human health</li>
        <li>Discovering low-cost non-invasive biomarkers</li>
        </ul>
        <a href="ealm.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
    <hr />
    <h4>Postdocs</h4>

    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/ilana_brito1.jpg" width="150" alt="Ilana"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Ilana Brito</font><br/>
        My main interest is understanding how microbes (and their genes)
        are transmitted among individuals and between individuals and
        their environments.
        <a href="ilana_brito.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
   
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/corzett2.jpg" width="150" alt="mBansal"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Christopher Corzett</font><br/>
        I am interested in how microbes survive and thrive in diverse and dynamic
    environments. This includes understanding how bacteria sense and respond to
    environmental change, the metabolic machinery required for different feeding
    strategies, and how microbes adapt and evolve various lifestyles... <a href="corzett.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
   
     <div id="member">
         <img class="floatLeft" src="img/groussin1.jpg" width="150" alt="mathieu"/>
         <font class="fontTitle">Mathieu Groussin</font><br/>
         Broadly speaking, I am interested in the inference of biological
         properties of ancient prokaryotic life and in how bacterial and archaeal
         communities evolve. My main interests focus on the study of genetic data
         (DNA, proteins) to understand the main evolutionary processes... <a href="mathieu_groussin.html">Read more</a>
     </div>

     <div id="member">
         <img class="floatLeft" src="img/thomas_gurry1.jpg" width="150" alt="thomas"/>
         <font class="fontTitle">Thomas Gurry</font><br/>
         The relationship between our health and our microbial inhabitants is poorly 
         understood and likely to be vast in its implications.  I am interested 
         in integrating different types of physiological data that have been collected 
         in a continuous fashion, including data pertaining to the microbiome... <a href="thomas_gurry.html">Read more</a>
     </div>

      <div id="member">
          <img class="floatLeft" src="img/tami_lieberman1.jpg" width="150" alt="tami"/>
          <font class="fontTitle">Tami Lieberman</font><br/>
          During my doctoral research in Roy Kishony's lab, I developed new genomic approaches
          for understanding how bacteria evolve during infections of individual people.
          I also studied antibiotic resistance and microbial evolution more broadly,
          using my favorite tools of experimental evolution and genomic sequencing. <a href="tami_lieberman.html">Read more</a>
      </div>

      <div id="member">
          <img class="floatLeft" src="img/josh_michener0.jpg" width="150" alt="josh"/>
          <font class="fontTitle">Josh Michener</font><br/>
          No gene exists in isolation. To be useful, a gene must be functionally
          expressed and its host must be able to deal with any resulting stresses.
          Most genes have had sufficient time in their current host that the gene
          and host have co-evolved to minimize deleterious interactions... <a href="josh_michener.html">Read more</a>
      </div>

    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/1_Mark_Smith.jpeg" width="150" alt="smith"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Mark Smith</font><br/>
        Mark's research uses high-throughput sequencing to gain insights into the structure, 
        function and dynamics of the human microbiome, with a recent publication on the topic 
        in <i>Nature</i>. <a href="http://www.openbiome.org/team/">Read more</a>
        <br/><br/><br/><br/>
    </div>

    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/12_Manu_Tamminen.jpeg" width="150" alt="manuTamminen"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Manu Tamminen</font><br/>
        I'm investigating novel approaches to extract and analyze genomic and transcriptomic
        information from single cells. To achieve this exciting objective I use a variety of
        tools, including flow assisted cell sorting, microfluidics, molecular biology and
        computational analysis. This combination of laboratory and computational approaches
        has considerable benefits over metagenomics... <a href="mvtammin.html">Read more</a>
    </div>

    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/avihu2.jpg" width="150" alt="avihu"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Avihu Yona</font><br/>
        During my doctoral research I utilized experimental evolution to study
        the evolutionary dynamics of genomic duplications like aneuploidy and
        tRNA genes. Now, I’m interested in the way complex communities evolve as
        an integral entity and in how evolutionary forces can be applied to
        reshape such communities towards desirable traits.... <a href="avihuYona.html">Read more</a>
       

    </div>  
     <hr/>
    <h4>Staff</h4>
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/antolik1.jpg" width="150" alt="seanClarke"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Caroline Antolik</font><br/>
        As Technical Assistant in the Alm lab, I help out with various
        aspects of lab members' projects. My main responsibilities include 16s
        library prep for Illumina sequencing and training for users on
        specialized equipment such as our Bioanalyzer and liquid handling robot.... <a href="antolik.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
    <hr/>
    
    <h4>Graduate Students</h4>
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/nathaniel_chu1.jpg" width="150" alt="Nathaniel"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Nathaniel Chu</font><br/>
        I am fascinated by two questions: What processes govern the evolution
        and ecology of microbial communities? And how can we harness these 
        processes to create practical solutions to problems in human and 
        ecological health? <a href="nathaniel_chu.html">Read more</a>
    </div>

    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/claire_duvallet1.jpg" width="150" alt="Claire"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Claire Duvallet</font><br/>
        Studying the relationships between the microbiome, health, and lifestyle 
        provides incredible opportunities for translational medical discoveries 
        and public health impacts. I'm excited by the possibility of using various 
        physiological data to predict disease states, both on the individualized 
        and broader community levels. <a href="claire_duvallet.html">Read more</a>
    </div>

    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/SeanPhoto1.jpg" width="150" alt="seanKearny"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Sean Kearney</font><br/>
        Microbes rule the world; our very existence is dependent on the once
        free-living oxygen-respiring bacteria now known as mitochondria. We
        cannot even begin to imagine how interlocked our own lives are with
        those of 4000 million year old organisms. I am interested in studying
        how microorganisms influence evolution and ecology over vast temporal
        and spatial scales.... <a href="skearney.html">Read more</a>
    </div>

    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/lttu_nguyen0.jpg" width="150" alt="tu"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Tu Nguyen</font><br/>
        Our body is in constant interaction with the microbial communities inhabiting 
        not only our gastrointestinal tract but also our respiratory system, skin 
        and the reproductive tissues. These diverse microbial communities outnumber 
        our own cells by a 10 to 1 ratio and have been increasingly reported to 
        play important roles in human health and diseases... <a href="lttu_nguyen.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
     
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/scotto_3.png" width="150" alt="scott"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Scott Olesen</font><br/>
        Microbial metabolisms transform the world around us, mediating key
        geochemical cycles and even determining human scent. I combine
        experimental design and computational techniques to assess and engineer
        the role of microbes in the environment and the human microbiome...<a href="scott_olesen.html">Read more</a> 
    </div>
    
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/12_Allison_Perrota.jpeg" width="150" alt="allison"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Allison Perrotta</font><br/>
        My current focus in the lab is to create and test high throughput
        methods for preparing 16s Illumina sequencing libraries from diverse
        environmental sources. Our lab researches the microbial ecology found in
        a myriad of environments and under diverse conditions... <a href="aperrott.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
    
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/shapeimage_4-1.png" width="150" alt="smillie"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Chris Smillie</font><br/>
        I'm interested in using computational methods to study the evolution and
        ecology of the human microbiome. Previously, I've collaborated with
        Sarah, Eli, and Paco to develop SLiME, a tool that uses machine learning
        to identify microbial signatures associated with disease... <a href="csmillie.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
    
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/sspencer1.jpg" width="150" alt="spencer"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Sarah Spencer</font><br/>
        I'm interested in how ecological principles play out at the resolution
        of single cells. To explore this I'm developing high-throughput
        sequencing technology that can immobilize interacting cells for
        downstream 16S profiling. I'm starting to apply this technique to
        aquatic communities, but eventually I'd like to adapt the protocol to
        address other problems in microbial evolution and ecology.
        <a href="sspencer.html">Read more</a>
    </div>


    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/joy_yang1.jpg" width="150" alt="yang"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Joy Yang</font><br/>
        I am broadly interested in the evolution and ecology of pathogens.
        In particular, I would like to utililize high performance computing
        to study the effect of the intricate interactions among host, bacteria,
        and mobile genetic elements such as phage and plasmids on disease.
        <a href="joy_yang.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
    
    
    <br />
    <hr />
    </contentPane>
    
    <rightPane>
    <br/>
    Current Members
    <div id="memberDir">
    <ul>
         <li><a href="ealm.html" class="nodec">Eric Alm</a></li>
         <li><a href="antolik.html" class="nodec">Caroline Antolik</a></li>
         <li><a href="ilana_brito.html" class="nodec">Ilana Brito</a></li>
         <li><a href="nathaniel_chu.html" class="nodec">Nathaniel Chu</a></li>
         <li><a href="saclarke.html" class="nodec">Sean Clarke</a></li>
         <li><a href="corzett.html" class="nodec">Christopher Corzett</a></li>
         <li><a href="claire_duvallet.html" class="nodec">Claire Duvallet</a></li>
         <li><a href="mathieu_groussin.html" class="nodec">Mathieu Groussin</a></li>
         <li><a href="skearney.html" class="nodec">Sean Kearney</a></li>
         <li><a href="thomas_gurry.html" class="nodec">Thomas Gurry</a></li>
         <li><a href="tami_lieberman.html" class="nodec">Tami Lieberman</a></li>
         <li><a href="josh_michener.html" class="nodec">Josh Michener</a></li>
         <li><a href="lttu_nguyen.html" class="nodec">Tu Nguyen</a></li>
         <li><a href="scott_olesen.html" class="nodec">Scott Olesen</a></li>
         <li><a href="aperrott.html" class="nodec">Allison Perrotta</a></li>
         <li><a href="csmillie.html" class="nodec">Chris Smillie</a></li>
         <li><a href="mbsmith.html" class="nodec">Mark Smith</a></li>
         <li><a href="sspencer.html" class="nodec">Sarah Spencer</a></li>
         <li><a href="mvtammin.html" class="nodec">Manu Tamminen</a></li>
         <li>Yaniv Turgeman</li>
         <li><a href="joy_yang.html" class="nodec">Joy Yang</a></li>
         <li><a href="avihuYona.html" class="nodec">Avihu Yona</a></li>
         <li>Annie Yu</li>
         <li>Shijie (Jay) Zhao</li>
    </ul>
    </div>
    <br/>
    Former Members
    <div id="memberDir">
    <ul>
    <li><a href="http://www.engr.uconn.edu/~mukul/ " class="external">Mukul Bansal</a></li>    
    <li><a href="http://microfluidics.epfl.ch/twiki/bin/view/MaerklLab/LbncPeople" class="external">Matthew Blackburn</a></li>
    <li><a href="franciscocamas.html" class="nodec">Francisco Camas</a></li>
    <li><a href="http://www.ladlab.org" class="external">Lawrence David</a></li>
    <li><a href="http://eapsweb.mit.edu/people/g4nier" class="external">Greg Fournier</a></li>
    <li>Jonathan Friedman</li>
    <li><a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/arnematerna" class="external">Arne Materna</a></li>
    <li><a href="elipapa.html" class="nodec">Eli Papa</a></li>
    <li><a href="http://www.shapirolab.ca/" class="external">B. Jesse Shapiro</a></li>
    <li><a href="http://engineering.jhu.edu/dogee/faculty/sarah-preheim/" class="external">Sarah Preheim</a></li>
    
    <li><a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/sonia-timberlake/65/283/b13" class="external">Sonia Timberlake</a></li>
    </ul>
    </div>
         
    </rightPane>
    <midPane>
    
    </midPane>
   
    
    <footer>
       
    </footer>
</Document>
