<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
    
<Title>Alm Lab Publications</Title>

<contentPane>
<h3>Highlights</h3>

<a href="http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/vaop/ncurrent/full/nature18927.html" target="_blank_">
Mobile genes in the human microbiome are structured from global to individual scales</a>
<div id="abstract">
<h4>Nature 2016. doi:10.1038/nature18927. </h4>

I. L. Brito, S. Yilmaz, K. Huang, L. Xu, S. D. Jupiter, A. P. Jenkins, W. Naisilisili, 
M. Tamminen, C. S. Smillie, J. R. Wortman, B. W. Birren, R. J. Xavier, 
P. C. Blainey, A. K. Singh, D. Gevers, E. J. Alm <br/>
<p/>
<img class="floatLeft" src="img/fijicomp2.jpg" alt="figure3" width="350"/>

<h4>Abstract</h4>
Recent work has underscored the importance of the microbiome in human health, and 
has largely attributed differences in phenotype to differences in the species present 
among individuals. However, mobile genes can confer profoundly different 
phenotypes on different strains of the same species. Little is known about the function 
and distribution of mobile genes in the human microbiome, and in particular whether the 
gene pool is globally homogenous or constrained by human population structure. Here, 
we investigate this question by comparing the mobile genes found in the microbiomes 
of 81 metropolitan North Americans with those of 172 agrarian Fiji islanders using a 
combination of single-cell genomics and metagenomics. We find large differences in 
mobile gene content between the Fijian and North American microbiomes, with functional 
variation that mirrors known dietary differences such as the excess of plant-based 
starch degradation genes found in Fijian individuals. Notably, we also observed 
differences between the mobile gene pools of neighbouring Fijian villages, even though 
microbiome composition across villages is similar. Finally, we observe high rates of 
recombination leading to individual-specific mobile elements, suggesting that the 
abundance of some genes may reflect environmental selection rather than dispersal 
limitation. Together, these data support the hypothesis that human activities and 
behaviours provide selective pressures that shape mobile gene pools, and that acquisition 
of mobile genes is important for colonizing specific human populations.
<br/><br/><br/><hr/><br/><br/>

</div>

<a href="http://www.nature.com/ismej/journal/v10/n2/full/ismej2015124a.html" target="_blank_">Massively parallel sequencing 
of single cells by epicPCR links functional genes with phylogenetic markers</a>
<div id="abstract">
<h4>ISME J. 2016 Feb; 10(2):427-36. </h4>

Spencer SJ, Tamminen MV, Preheim SP, Guo MT, Briggs AW, Brito IL, A Weitz D, Pitkänen LK, 
Vigneault F, Juhani Virta MP, Alm EJ. <br/>

Computational and Systems Biology, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA, USA.
<p/>
<img class="floatLeft" src="img/epic_pcr.jpg" alt="figure3" width="350"/>

<h4>Abstract</h4>
Many microbial communities are characterized by high genetic diversity. 
16S ribosomal RNA sequencing can determine community members, and metagenomics 
can determine the functional diversity, but resolving the functional role of 
individual cells in high throughput remains an unsolved challenge. Here, we 
describe epicPCR (Emulsion, Paired Isolation and Concatenation PCR), a new 
technique that links functional genes and phylogenetic markers in uncultured 
single cells, providing a throughput of hundreds of thousands of cells with 
costs comparable to one genomic library preparation. We demonstrate the utility 
of our technique in a natural environment by profiling a sulfate-reducing 
community in a freshwater lake, revealing both known sulfate reducers and 
discovering new putative sulfate reducers. Our method is adaptable to any 
conserved genetic trait and translates genetic associations from diverse 
microbial samples into a sequencing library that answers targeted ecological 
questions. Potential applications include identifying functional community 
members, tracing horizontal gene transfer networks and mapping ecological 
interactions between microbial cells.
<br/><br/><br/><hr/><br/><br/>

</div>

<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4720164/" target="_blank_">Detection of low-abundance 
bacterial strains in metagenomic datasets by eigengenome partitioning</a>
<div id="abstract">
<h4>Nature Biotechnology. 2015 Oct; 33(10):1053-60. </h4>

Cleary B, Brito IL, Huang K, Gevers D, Shea T, Young S, Alm EJ.
<br/>

Computational and Systems Biology, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA, USA.
<p/>
<img class="floatLeft" src="img/lsa.jpg" alt="figure3" width="350"/>

<h4>Abstract</h4>
Analyses of metagenomic datasets that are sequenced to a depth of billions or 
trillions of bases can uncover hundreds of microbial genomes, but naive assembly 
of these data is computationally intensive, requiring hundreds of gigabytes to 
terabytes of RAM. We present latent strain analysis (LSA), a scalable, de novo 
pre-assembly method that separates reads into biologically informed partitions 
and thereby enables assembly of individual genomes. LSA is implemented with a 
streaming calculation of unobserved variables that we call eigengenomes. 
Eigengenomes reflect covariance in the abundance of short, fixed-length 
sequences, or k-mers. As the abundance of each genome in a sample is reflected 
in the abundance of each k-mer in that genome, eigengenome analysis can be used 
to partition reads from different genomes. This partitioning can be done in fixed 
memory using tens of gigabytes of RAM, which makes assembly and downstream analyses 
of terabytes of data feasible on commodity hardware. Using LSA, we assemble partial 
and near-complete genomes of bacterial taxa present at relative abundances as 
low as 0.00001%. We also show that LSA is sensitive enough to separate reads 
from several strains of the same species.

<br/><br/><br/><hr/><br/><br/>

</div>


<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25313052" target="_blank_">Transfer of noncoding 
DNA drives regulatory rewiring in bacteria
</a>
<div id="abstract">

<h4>PNAS. 2014 Nov 11; 111(45):16112-7.</h4>
<img class="floatLeft" src="img/Oren_fig1.jpg" alt="figure3" width="350"/>

Oren Y, Smith MB, Johns NI, Kaplan Zeevi M, Biran D, Ron EZ, Corander J, 
Wang HH, Alm EJ, Pupko T.
<br/>
<p/>
<h4>Abstract</h4>
Understanding the mechanisms that generate variation is a common pursuit unifying 
the life sciences. Bacteria represent an especially striking puzzle, because closely 
related strains possess radically different metabolic and ecological capabilities. 
Differences in protein repertoire arising from gene transfer are currently 
considered the primary mechanism underlying phenotypic plasticity in bacteria. 
Although bacterial coding plasticity has been extensively studied in previous decades, 
little is known about the role that regulatory plasticity plays in bacterial evolution. 
Here, we show that bacterial genes can rapidly shift between multiple regulatory 
modes by acquiring functionally divergent nonhomologous promoter regions. Through 
analysis of 270,000 regulatory regions across 247 genomes, we demonstrate that 
regulatory "switching" to nonhomologous alternatives is ubiquitous, occurring 
across the bacterial domain. Using comparative transcriptomics, we show that at 
least 16% of the expression divergence between Escherichia coli strains can be 
explained by this regulatory switching. Further, using an oligonucleotide regulatory 
library, we establish that switching affects bacterial promoter architecture. We 
provide evidence that regulatory switching can occur through horizontal regulatory 
transfer, which allows regulatory regions to move across strains, and even genera, 
independently from the genes they regulate. Finally, by experimentally characterizing 
the fitness effect of a regulatory transfer on a pathogenic E. coli strain, we 
demonstrate that regulatory switching elicits important phenotypic consequences. 
Taken together, our findings expose previously unappreciated regulatory 
plasticity in bacteria and provide a gateway for understanding bacterial 
phenotypic variation and adaptation.
<br/><br/><br/><hr/><br/><br/>
</div>


<a href="http://www.nature.com/news/policy-how-to-regulate-faecal-transplants-1.14720" target="_blank_">Policy: How to regulate faecal transplants.</a>
<div id="abstract">

<h4>Nature. 2014 Feb 19 </h4>
<img class="floatLeft" src="img/Stool-1.jpg" alt="stool" width="350"/>

<h4>For medical use, human stool should be considered a tissue, not a drug, argue Mark B Smith, Colleen Kelly and Eric J Alm.</h4>

<br/>Related links: <br/>
<a href="http://www.openbiome.org/" target="_blank">OpenBiome.org</a><br/>
<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/18/health/a-new-kind-of-transplant-bank.html?_r=0" target="_blank">In New York Times</a>
<br/><br/><br/><br/><br/><br/><br/><br/><br/><hr/><br/><br/>
</div>

<a href="https://genomebiology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/gb-2014-15-7-r89" target="_blank_">Host 
lifestyle affects human microbiota on daily timescales.</a>
<div id="abstract">
<h4>Genome Biol. 2014;15(7):R89. </h4>

David LA, Materna AC, Friedman J, Campos-Baptista MI, Blackburn MC, Perrotta A, Erdman SE, Alm EJ. <br/>

Computational and Systems Biology Initiative, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Massachusetts 02139, USA.
.<p/>
<img class="floatLeft" src="img/HUGE_fig1.jpg" alt="figure3" width="350"/>

<h4>Abstract</h4>
Disturbance to human microbiota may underlie several pathologies. Here, we link 
over 10,000 longitudinal measurements of human wellness and action to the daily 
gut and salivary microbiota dynamics of two individuals over the course of one year. 
These time series show overall microbial communities to be stable for months. 
However, rare events in each subjects’ life rapidly and broadly impacted 
microbiota dynamics. Travel from the developed to the developing world in one 
subject led to a nearly two-fold increase in the Bacteroidetes to Firmicutes ratio, 
which reversed upon return. Enteric infection in the other subject resulted in 
the permanent decline of most gut bacterial taxa, which were replaced by genetically 
similar species. Still, even during periods of overall community stability, the 
dynamics of select microbial taxa could be associated with specific host behaviors. 
Most prominently, changes in host fiber intake positively correlated with next-day 
abundance changes among 15% of gut microbiota members. Our findings suggest that 
although human-associated microbial communities are generally stable, they can 
be quickly and profoundly altered by common human actions and experiences.


<h3>Publication related</h3>
<a href="mit_daily_timeseries.html">Metadata for EBI Study: ERP006059</a><br/>

<br/><br/><br/><hr/><br/><br/>

</div>

<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22491847" target="_blank_">Population genomics of early events in the ecological differentiation of
bacteria.</a>
<div id="abstract">

<h4>Science. 2012 Apr 6;336(6077):48-51. </h4>
<img class="floatLeft" src="img/F3.cropped.png" alt="figure3" width="350"/>

Shapiro BJ, Friedman J, Cordero OX, Preheim SP, Timberlake SC, Szabó G, Polz MF, 
Alm EJ.<br/>

Program in Computational and Systems Biology, Massachusetts Institute of
Technology, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA.<p/>
<h4>Abstract</h4>
Genetic exchange is common among bacteria, but its effect on population diversity
during ecological differentiation remains controversial. A fundamental question
is whether advantageous mutations lead to selection of clonal genomes or, as in
sexual eukaryotes, sweep through populations on their own. Here, we show that in 
two recently diverged populations of ocean bacteria, ecological differentiation
has occurred akin to a sexual mechanism: A few genome regions have swept through 
subpopulations in a habitat-specific manner, accompanied by gradual separation of
gene pools as evidenced by increased habitat specificity of the most recent
recombinations. These findings reconcile previous, seemingly contradictory
empirical observations of the genetic structure of bacterial populations and
point to a more unified process of differentiation in bacteria and sexual
eukaryotes than previously thought.

<br/><br/><br/><hr/><br/><br/>
</div>



<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22037308" target="_blank_">Ecology drives a global network of gene exchange connecting the
human microbiome.</a>
<div id="abstract">
<h4>Nature. 2011 Oct 30;480(7376):241-4. </h4>

Chris S Smillie; Mark B Smith; Jonathan Friedman; Otto X Cordero; Lawrence A David; Eric J Alm <br/>

Computational and Systems Biology Initiative, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Massachusetts 02139, USA.
.<p/>
<img class="floatLeft" src="img/nature10571-f3.2.jpeg" alt="figure3" width="350"/>

<h4>Abstract</h4>
Horizontal gene transfer (HGT), the acquisition of genetic material from
non-parental lineages, is known to be important in bacterial evolution. In
particular, HGT provides rapid access to genetic innovations, allowing traits
such as virulence, antibiotic resistance and xenobiotic metabolism to spread
through the human microbiome. Recent anecdotal studies providing snapshots of
active gene flow on the human body have highlighted the need to determine the
frequency of such recent transfers and the forces that govern these events. Here
we report the discovery and characterization of a vast, human-associated network
of gene exchange, large enough to directly compare the principal forces shaping
HGT. We show that this network of 10,770 unique, recently transferred (more than
99% nucleotide identity) genes found in 2,235 full bacterial genomes, is shaped
principally by ecology rather than geography or phylogeny, with most gene
exchange occurring between isolates from ecologically similar, but
geographically separated, environments. For example, we observe 25-fold more HGT
between human-associated bacteria than among ecologically diverse non-human
isolates (P = 3.0 x 10(-270)). We show that within the human microbiome this
ecological architecture continues across multiple spatial scales, functional
classes and ecological niches with transfer further enriched among bacteria that
inhabit the same body site, have the same oxygen tolerance or have the same
ability to cause disease. This structure offers a window into the molecular
traits that define ecological niches, insight that we use to uncover sources of
antibiotic resistance and identify genes associated with the pathology of
meningitis and other diseases.
<br/><br/><br/><hr/><br/><br/>

</div>

<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21170026" target="_blank_">Rapid evolutionary innovation during an Archaean genetic expansion.</a>
<div id="abstract">
<h4>Nature. 2011 Jan 6;469(7328):93-6. </h4>
David LA, Alm EJ. <br/>

Computational and Systems Biology Initiative, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Massachusetts 02139, USA.
.<br/>
<img class="floatLeft" src="img/nature09649-f1.2.jpeg" alt="figure3" width="350"/>

<h4>Abstract</h4>
The natural history of Precambrian life is still unknown because of the rarity
of microbial fossils and biomarkers. However, the composition of modern-day
genomes may bear imprints of ancient biogeochemical events. Here we use an
explicit model of macroevolution including gene birth, transfer, duplication and
loss events to map the evolutionary history of 3,983 gene families across the
three domains of life onto a geological timeline. Surprisingly, we find that a
brief period of genetic innovation during the Archaean eon, which coincides with
a rapid diversification of bacterial lineages, gave rise to 27% of major modern
gene families. A functional analysis of genes born during this Archaean
expansion reveals that they are likely to be involved in electron-transport and
respiratory pathways. Genes arising after this expansion show increasing use of
molecular oxygen (P = 3.4 x 10(-8)) and redox-sensitive transition metals and
compounds, which is consistent with an increasingly oxygenating biosphere.
</div>
</contentPane>
<rightPane>
<br/>
<h4>Alm Lab Publication Links</h4>
<div id="title">
<a href="http://scholar.google.com/citations?user=IdcugBgAAAAJ" class="external">Google Scholar</a><br></br>
<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=Alm+EJ" class="external">PubMed</a>
</div><br/>

<!--2014-->
<!--<h4>Publication Related</h4>-->
<!--<div id="pubmed">-->
    <!--<div id="journal">Lawrence A David, Arne C Materna, Jonathan Friedman, Maria Ines C Baptista, Matthew C Blackburn, Allison Perrotta, Susan E Erdman, Eric J Alm<br/>-->
    <!--Genome Biol 15(7)<br/>-->
    <!--<a href="mit_daily_timeseries.html">metadata</a><br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title">Host lifestyle affects human microbiota on daily timescales.</div>-->
<!--</div><br/>--> 

<!--<div id="pubmed">-->
    <!--<div id="journal">Zain Kassam, Mark B Smith, Eric J Alm<br/>-->
    <!--New England Journal of Medicine, accepted (2014)<br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title">Bridging the science gap in diabetes and obesity: Integrating the microbiome into clinical trials.</div>-->
<!--</div><br/>  -->

<!--<div id="pubmed">-->
    <!--<div id="journal">Jessica R Lakritz, Theofilos Poutahidis, Tatiana Levkovich, Bernard J Varian, Yassin M Ibrahim, Antonis Chatzigiagkos, Sheyla Mirabal, Eric Alm, Susan E Erdman-->
    <!--International Journal of Cancer (2014)<br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24382758">Beneficial bacteria stimulate host immune cells to mammary cancer in mice.</a></div>-->

<!--</div><br/>-->

<!--<div id="pubmed">-->
	<!--<div id="journal">-->
	<!--Ilan Youngster, Jenny Sauk, Christina Pindar, Robin G Wilson, Jess L Kaplan, Mark B Smith, Eric J Alm, Dirk Gevers, George H Russel, Elizabeth L Hohmann-->
	<!--Clinical Infectious Diseases (2014)<br/>-->
	<!--</div>-->
	<!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24762631">Fecal microbiota transplant for relapsing Clostridium difficile infection using a frozen inoculum from unrelated donors: a randomized, open-label, controlled pilot study.</a></div>-->

<!--</div><br/>-->

<!--<div id="pubmed">-->
    <!--<div id="journal">Daniel H Rothman, Gregory P Fournier, Katherine L French, Eric J Alm, Edward A Boyle, Changqun Cao, Roger E Summons<br/>-->
    <!--PNAS (2014)<br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24706773">Methanogenic burst in the end-Permian carbon cycle.</a></div>-->

<!--</div><br/>-->

<!--<div id="pubmed">-->
    <!--<div id="journal">Mark B Smith, Colleen Kelly, Eric J Alm<br/>-->
    <!--Nature (2014)<br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.nature.com/news/policy-how-to-regulate-faecal-transplants-1.14720">Policy: How to regulate faecal transplants.</a></div>-->
    <!---->
<!--</div><br/>-->

<!--<div id="pubmed">-->
    <!--<div id="journal">Theofilos Poutahidis, Alex Springer, Tatiana Levkovich, Peimin Qi, Bernard J Varian, jessica R Lakritz, Yassin M Ibrahim, Antonis Chatzigiagkos, Eric J Alm, Susan E Erdman<br/>-->
    <!--PLoS One (2014)<br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24392159">Probiotic microbes sustain yourful serum testosterone levels and testicular size in aging mice.</a></div>-->
    <!---->
<!--</div><br/>-->
    <!---->
    <!--2013-->
<!--<div id="pubmed">   -->

    <!--<div id="journal">Sarah P Preheim, Allison R Perrotta, Antonio M Martin-Platero, Anika Gupta, Eric J Alm<br/>-->
    <!--Appl. Environ. Microbiol. (2013)<br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24060130">Computational methods for high-throughput comparative analyses of natural microbial communities.</a></div>-->
    <!---->
<!--</div><br/>-->

<!--<div id="pubmed">   -->

    <!--<div id="journal">Jessica R Lakritz, Theofilos Poutahidis, Tatiana Levkovich, Bernard J Varian, Yassin M Ibrahim, Antonis Chatzigiagkos, Sheyla Mirabal, Eric J Alm, Susan E Erdman<br/>-->
    <!--International Journal of Cancer (2013)<br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24382758">Beneficial bacteria stimulate host immune cells to counteract dietary and genetic predisposition to mammary cancer in mice.</a></div>-->
    <!---->
<!--</div><br/>-->

<!--<div id="pubmed">   -->

    <!--<div id="journal">Mukul S Bansal, Eric J Alm, Manolis Kellis<br/>-->
    <!--Journal of Computational Biology (2013)<br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24033262">Reconciliation revisited: handling multiple optima when reconciling with duplication, transfer and loss.</a></div>-->
    <!---->
<!--</div><br/>-->
    <!---->
    <!--<div id="pubmed">-->
    <!--<div id="journal">Gitta Szabo, Sarah P Preheim, Kathryn M Kauffman, Lawrence A David, Jesse Shapiro, Eric J Alm, Martin F Polz<br/>-->
    <!--The ISME Journal (2013)<br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23178668">Reproducibility of Vibrionaceae population structure in costal bacterioplankton.</a></div>-->
    <!---->
<!--</div><br/>-->
    <!---->
    <!--<div id="pubmed">-->
    <!--<div id="journal">Martin F Polz, Eric J Alm, William P Hanage<br/>-->
    <!--Trends in Genetics (2013)<br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23332119">Horizontal gene transfer and the evolution of bacterial and archaeal population structure.</a></div>-->
    <!---->
<!--</div><br/>-->
    <!---->
<!--<div id="pubmed">-->
    <!--<div id="journal">Jonathan Friedman, Eric J Alm, B Jesse Shapiro<br/>-->
    <!--PLOS ONE. (2013)<br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23349716">Sympatric speciation: when is it possible in bacteria?</a></div>-->
 <!---->
<!--</div><br/>-->

    <!--2012-->
    <!---->


<!--<div id="pubmed">-->
    <!---->
    <!--<div id="journal">Jonathan Friedman, Eric J Alm<br/>-->
    <!--PLoS Comput Biol. (2012)<br/>-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23028285">Inferring correlation networks from genomic survey data.</a>-->
    <!--</div>-->
<!--</div><br/>-->

<!--<div id="pubmed">-->
    <!--<div id="journal">Arne C Materna; Jonathan Friedman; Claudia Bauer; Christina David; Sara Chen; Ivy B Huang; April Gillens; Sean A Clarke;-->
<!--Martin F Polz; Eric J Alm<br />-->
<!--The ISME journal (2012)-->
    <!--</div>-->
    <!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22832347">Shape and evolution of the-->
<!--fundamental niche in marine Vibrio.</a>-->
    <!--</div>-->
<!--</div><br />-->

<!--<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Eliseo Papa; Michael Docktor; Christopher Smillie; Sarah Weber; Sarah P Preheim; Dirk Gevers; Georgia Giannoukos; Dawn Ciulla; Diana Tabbaa; Jay Ingram; David B Schauer; Doyle V Ward; Joshua R Korzenik; Ramnik J Xavier; Athos Bousvaros; Eric J Alm<br />-->

<!--PloS one (2012)</div>-->
<!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22768065">Non-invasive mapping of the gastrointestinal microbiota identifies children with inflammatory bowel disease.</a></div>-->
<!--</div><br />-->

<!--<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Mukul S Bansal; Eric J Alm; Manolis Kellis<br />-->

<!--Bioinformatics (Oxford, England) (2012)</div>-->
<!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22689773">Efficient algorithms for the reconciliation problem with gene duplication, horizontal transfer and loss.</a></div>-->
<!--</div><br />-->

<!--<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">B Jesse Shapiro; Jonathan Friedman; Otto X Cordero; Sarah P Preheim; Sonia C Timberlake; Gitta Szab; Martin F Polz; Eric J Alm<br />-->

<!--Science (New York, N.Y.) (2012)</div>-->
<!--<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22491847">Population genomics of early events in the ecological differentiation of bacteria.</a></div>-->
<!--</div><br />-->



<!--More Publications <a href="publications_more.html">1998-2011</a>.-->


</rightPane>
<midPane></midPane>
<footer></footer>
</Document>
