<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
    <!-- replace the contents in the brackets, erase the brackets themselves-->
    <Title>Publications from 1998-2011 </Title> 

    <contentPane>
<h3>Publications from 1998-2011</h3>
    <a href="publications.html">Click Here for 2012-present.</a><br/>
    2011
<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Gregory P Fournier; Cheryl P Andam; Eric J Alm; J Peter Gogarten<br />

Origins of life and evolution of the biosphere : the journal of the International Society for the Study of the Origin of Life (2011)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22200905">Molecular evolution of aminoacyl tRNA synthetase proteins in the early history of life.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Chris S Smillie; Mark B Smith; Jonathan Friedman; Otto X Cordero; Lawrence A David; Eric J Alm<br />

Nature (2011)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22037308">Ecology drives a global network of gene exchange connecting the human microbiome.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Lianrong Wang; Shi Chen; Kevin L Vergin; Stephen J Giovannoni; Simon W Chan; Michael S DeMott; Koli Taghizadeh; Otto X Cordero; Michael Cutler; Sonia Timberlake; Eric J Alm; Martin F Polz; Jarone Pinhassi; Zixin Deng; Peter C Dedon<br />

Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America (2011)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21285367">DNA phosphorothioation is widespread and quantized in bacterial genomes.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Lawrence A David; Eric J Alm<br />

Nature (2011)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21170026">Rapid evolutionary innovation during an Archaean genetic expansion.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Sarah P Preheim; Yan Boucher; Hans Wildschutte; Lawrence A David; Daniele Veneziano; Eric J Alm; Martin F Polz<br />

Environmental microbiology (2011)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20819104">Metapopulation structure of Vibrionaceae among coastal marine invertebrates.</a></div>
</div><br />

    2010
<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Francisco M Camas; Eric J Alm; Juan F Poyatos<br />

PLoS computational biology (2010)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21085639">Local gene regulation details a recognition code within the LacI transcriptional factor family.</a></div>
</div><br />
<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Sbastien Rodrigue; Arne C Materna; Sonia C Timberlake; Matthew C Blackburn; Rex R Malmstrom; Eric J Alm; Sallie W Chisholm<br />

PloS one (2010)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20676378">Unlocking short read sequencing for metagenomics.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Zhili He; Aifen Zhou; Edward Baidoo; Qiang He; Marcin P Joachimiak; Peter Benke; Richard Phan; Aindrila Mukhopadhyay; Christopher L Hemme; Katherine Huang; Eric J Alm; Matthew W Fields; Judy Wall; David Stahl; Terry C Hazen; Jay D Keasling; Adam P Arkin; Jizhong Zhou<br />

Applied and environmental microbiology (2010)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20038696">Global transcriptional, physiological, and metabolite analyses of the responses of Desulfovibrio vulgaris hildenborough to salt adaptation.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Paramvir S Dehal; Marcin P Joachimiak; Morgan N Price; John T Bates; Jason K Baumohl; Dylan Chivian; Greg D Friedland; Katherine H Huang; Keith Keller; Pavel S Novichkov; Inna L Dubchak; Eric J Alm; Adam P Arkin<br />

Nucleic acids research (2010)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19906701">MicrobesOnline: an integrated portal for comparative and functional genomics.</a></div>
</div><br />

    2009
<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">B Jesse Shapiro; Eric Alm<br />

The ISME journal (2009)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19458656">The slow:fast substitution ratio reveals changing patterns of natural selection in gamma-proteobacterial genomes.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">B Jesse Shapiro; Lawrence A David; Jonathan Friedman; Eric J Alm<br />

Trends in microbiology (2009)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19375326">Looking for Darwin's footprints in the microbial world.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Tasha A Desai; Dmitry A Rodionov; Mikhail S Gelfand; Eric J Alm; Christopher V Rao<br />

Nucleic acids research (2009)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19264798">Engineering transcription factors with novel DNA-binding specificity using comparative genomics.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Christophe Fraser; Eric J Alm; Martin F Polz; Brian G Spratt; William P Hanage<br />

Science (New York, N.Y.) (2009)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19197054">The bacterial species challenge: making sense of genetic and ecological diversity.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Alexey E Kazakov; Dmitry A Rodionov; Eric Alm; Adam Paul Arkin; Inna Dubchak; Mikhail S Gelfand<br />

Journal of bacteriology (2009)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18820024">Comparative genomics of regulation of fatty acid and branched-chain amino acid utilization in proteobacteria.</a></div>
</div><br />

2008
<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Dylan Chivian; Eoin L Brodie; Eric J Alm; David E Culley; Paramvir S Dehal; Todd Z DeSantis; Thomas M Gihring; Alla Lapidus; Li-Hung Lin; Stephen R Lowry; Duane P Moser; Paul M Richardson; Gordon Southam; Greg Wanger; Lisa M Pratt; Gary L Andersen; Terry C Hazen; Fred J Brockman; Adam P Arkin; Tullis C Onstott<br />

Science (New York, N.Y.) (2008)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18845759">Environmental genomics reveals a single-species ecosystem deep within Earth.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Dana E Hunt; Lawrence A David; Dirk Gevers; Sarah P Preheim; Eric J Alm; Martin F Polz<br />

Science (New York, N.Y.) (2008)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18497299">Resource partitioning and sympatric differentiation among closely related bacterioplankton.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">B Jesse Shapiro; Eric J Alm<br />

PLoS genetics (2008)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18266472">Comparing patterns of natural selection across species using selective signatures.</a></div>
</div><br />

2007
<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Sergey Stolyar; Qiang He; Marcin P Joachimiak; Zhili He; Zamin Koo Yang; Sharon E Borglin; Dominique C Joyner; Katherine Huang; Eric Alm; Terry C Hazen; Jizhong Zhou; Judy D Wall; Adam P Arkin; David A Stahl<br />

Journal of bacteriology (2007)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17921288">Response of Desulfovibrio vulgaris to alkaline stress.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Kelly S Bender; Huei-Che Bill Yen; Christopher L Hemme; Zamin Yang; Zhili He; Qiang He; Jizhong Zhou; Katherine H Huang; Eric J Alm; Terry C Hazen; Adam P Arkin; Judy D Wall<br />

Applied and environmental microbiology (2007)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17630305">Analysis of a ferric uptake regulator (Fur) mutant of Desulfovibrio vulgaris Hildenborough.</a></div>
</div><br />

2006
<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Eric Alm; Katherine Huang; Adam Arkin<br />

PLoS computational biology (2006)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17083272">The evolution of two-component systems in bacteria reveals different strategies for niche adaptation.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">M E Clark; Q He; Z He; K H Huang; E J Alm; X-F Wan; T C Hazen; A P Arkin; J D Wall; J-Z Zhou; M W Fields<br />

Applied and environmental microbiology (2006)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16885312">Temporal transcriptomic analysis as Desulfovibrio vulgaris Hildenborough transitions into stationary phase during electron donor depletion.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Morgan N Price; Adam P Arkin; Eric J Alm<br />

PLoS genetics (2006)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16789824">The life-cycle of operons.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Qiang He; Katherine H Huang; Zhili He; Eric J Alm; Matthew W Fields; Terry C Hazen; Adam P Arkin; Judy D Wall; Jizhong Zhou<br />

Applied and environmental microbiology (2006)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16751553">Energetic consequences of nitrite stress in Desulfovibrio vulgaris Hildenborough, inferred from global transcriptional analysis.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Aindrila Mukhopadhyay; Zhili He; Eric J Alm; Adam P Arkin; Edward E Baidoo; Sharon C Borglin; Wenqiong Chen; Terry C Hazen; Qiang He; Hoi-Ying Holman; Katherine Huang; Rick Huang; Dominique C Joyner; Natalie Katz; Martin Keller; Paul Oeller; Alyssa Redding; Jun Sun; Judy Wall; Jing Wei; Zamin Yang; Huei-Che Yen; Jizhong Zhou; Jay D Keasling<br />

Journal of bacteriology (2006)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16707698">Salt stress in Desulfovibrio vulgaris Hildenborough: an integrated genomics approach.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Morgan N Price; Eric J Alm; Adam P Arkin<br />

Journal of molecular evolution (2006)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16612542">The histidine operon is ancient.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">S R Chhabra; Q He; K H Huang; S P Gaucher; E J Alm; Z He; M Z Hadi; T C Hazen; J D Wall; J Zhou; A P Arkin; A K Singh<br />

Journal of bacteriology (2006)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16484192">Global analysis of heat shock response in Desulfovibrio vulgaris Hildenborough.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Adam B Leaphart; Dorothea K Thompson; Katherine Huang; Eric Alm; Xiu-Feng Wan; Adam Arkin; Steven D Brown; Liyou Wu; Tingfen Yan; Xueduan Liu; Gene S Wickham; Jizhong Zhou<br />

Journal of bacteriology (2006)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16452448">Transcriptome profiling of Shewanella oneidensis gene expression following exposure to acidic and alkaline pH.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Morgan N Price; Adam P Arkin; Eric J Alm<br />

BMC bioinformatics (2006)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16412220">OpWise: operons aid the identification of differentially expressed genes in bacterial microarray experiments.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Steven D Brown; Madhavi Martin; Sameer Deshpande; Sudipta Seal; Katherine Huang; Eric Alm; Yunfeng Yang; Liyou Wu; Tingfen Yan; Xueduan Liu; Adam Arkin; Karuna Chourey; Jizhong Zhou; Dorothea K Thompson<br />

Applied and environmental microbiology (2006)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16391131">Cellular response of Shewanella oneidensis to strontium stress.</a></div>
</div><br />

Pre-2006

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Dmitry A Rodionov; Inna L Dubchak; Adam P Arkin; Eric J Alm; Mikhail S Gelfand<br />

PLoS computational biology (2005)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16261196">Dissimilatory metabolism of nitrogen oxides in bacteria: comparative reconstruction of transcriptional networks.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Eric J Alm; Katherine H Huang; Morgan N Price; Richard P Koche; Keith Keller; Inna L Dubchak; Adam P Arkin<br />

Genome research (2005)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15998914">The MicrobesOnline Web site for comparative genomics.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Morgan N Price; Eric J Alm; Adam P Arkin<br />

Nucleic acids research (2005)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15942025">Interruptions in gene expression drive highly expressed operons to the leading strand of DNA replication.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Morgan N Price; Katherine H Huang; Adam P Arkin; Eric J Alm<br />

Genome research (2005)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15930492">Operon formation is driven by co-regulation and not by horizontal gene transfer.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Yongqing Liu; Weimin Gao; Yue Wang; Liyou Wu; Xueduan Liu; Tinfeng Yan; Eric Alm; Adam Arkin; Dorothea K Thompson; Matthew W Fields; Jizhong Zhou<br />

Journal of bacteriology (2005)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15774893">Transcriptome analysis of Shewanella oneidensis MR-1 in response to elevated salt conditions.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Morgan N Price; Katherine H Huang; Eric J Alm; Adam P Arkin<br />

Nucleic acids research (2005)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15701760">A novel method for accurate operon predictions in all sequenced prokaryotes.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Dmitry A Rodionov; Inna Dubchak; Adam Arkin; Eric Alm; Mikhail S Gelfand<br />

Genome biology (2004)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15535866">Reconstruction of regulatory and metabolic pathways in metal-reducing delta-proteobacteria.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Haichun Gao; Yue Wang; Xueduan Liu; Tingfen Yan; Liyou Wu; Eric Alm; Adam Arkin; Dorothea K Thompson; Jizhong Zhou<br />

Journal of bacteriology (2004)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15516594">Global transcriptome analysis of the heat shock response of Shewanella oneidensis.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Dmitry N Ivankov; Sergiy O Garbuzynskiy; Eric Alm; Kevin W Plaxco; David Baker; Alexei V Finkelstein<br />

Protein science : a publication of the Protein Society (2003)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12931003">Contact order revisited: influence of protein size on the folding rate.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Eric Alm; Adam P Arkin<br />

Current opinion in structural biology (2003)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12727512">Biological networks.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Eric Alm; Alexandre V Morozov; Tanja Kortemme; David Baker<br />

Journal of molecular biology (2002)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12217703">Simple physical models connect theory and experiment in protein folding kinetics.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">V Grantcharova; E J Alm; D Baker; A L Horwich<br />

Current opinion in structural biology (2001)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11179895">Mechanisms of protein folding.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">Q Yi; M L Scalley-Kim; E J Alm; D Baker<br />

Journal of molecular biology (2000)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/10873457">NMR characterization of residual structure in the denatured state of protein L.</a></div>
</div><br />

<div id="pubmed"><div id="journal">R A Cardullo; E J Alm<br />

Methods in cell biology (1998)</div>
<div id="title"><a class="external" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/9500134">Introduction to image processing.</a></div>
</div><br />

    </contentPane>
    
    <rightPane>
   
    </rightPane>
    <midPane>
        
    </midPane>
    <footer>
        <hr />
        <!--Evolutionary, Ecological and Environmental Systems Biology-->
        <img src="img/bar1.png" alt="bar1"/>
    </footer>
</Document>
