<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
    <Title>Alm Lab Member: Sean Gibbons </Title>

    <contentPane>
    <h3>Sean Gibbons</h3>
        <div id="member">
            <!-- rename the image file here. jpgs, pngs, whatever are fine. -->
        <img class="floatRight" src="img/sean_gibbons1.png" width="150"/>
        <h4>Research Interests</h4>
        Microorganisms form the foundation of all ecosystems on Earth and are
        responsible for driving the major biogeochemical cycles. From
        generating the air that we breathe and the food that we eat, to
        maintaining our health and well-being, microbial communities are
        essential components of the biosphere. Due to their size and rapid
        generation times, microbial ecosystems are perfect models for tackling
        complex ecological or evolutionary questions. My work exploits
        microbial systems to gain quantitative insight into the rules
        underlying ecological community assembly, stability, and ecosystem
        function.
        
        <br/><br/>
        <h4>Current Research</h4>
        My current work focuses on understanding the dynamics of human gut
        microbial communities. I am particularly interested in how changes in
        microbial frequencies covary within a fluctuating environment, and how
        these correlations are related to phylogenetic distance or life history
        strategies. I am also working in a mouse gut model to understand how
        gut community resilience and resistance to pathogen invasion is eroded
        by enviromental perturbations (e.g. antibiotic treatments or changes in
        diet).

        <!-- if you want another heading or subheading, copy those lines and repeat. or,
             if you don't need a subheading, just delete that line. -->

            <!-- rename the image file here. jpgs, pngs, whatever are fine. -->
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/sean_gibbons2.png" width="150" alt="image 2"/>
        <p/>
    </div>
    </contentPane>

    <rightPane>
        <br/>
        <div id="memberDir">
        <h4>Sean Gibbons</h4>
        Postdoctoral Associate<br/>
        Biological Engineering<br/>
        sgibbons [at] mit [dot] edu<br/>
        <p/>

        <h4>Education</h4>
        <ul>
        <li>PhD, biophysics, University of Chicago, 2015</li>
        <li>MSc, microbiology, Uppsala University, 2010</li>
        <li>BA, BSc, BA, molecular biology, microbiology, and French, University of Montana, 2008</li>
        </ul>
        <p/>
        <img class="floatRight" src="img/sean_gibbons3.png" width="150"/>
        </div>
    </rightPane>
        <!-- Don't change anything below here! -->
    <midPane>
    </midPane>
    <footer>
        <hr />
        <img src="img/bar1.png" alt="bar1"/>
    </footer>
</Document>
