<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
    <Title>Alm Lab Software: SHE-RA</Title>

    <contentPane>

    </contentPane>

    <rightPane>

    </rightPane>

    <midPane>
    <br/>
    <h4>SHE-RA </h4>
    <h5>SHortread Error-Reducing Aligner</h5>
    <div id="software">
    by Sonia Timberlake and Eric Alm <br/>
    soniat at mit.edu <p/>

    <img class="floatRight" src="img/30_SHE-RA.jpeg" alt="SHERA"/>
    The SHE-RA software turns error-prone short reads into Sanger-quality
    composite reads by aligning the overlapping ends of each matepair. Given a
    library of appropriately-sized inserts, paired-end reads of each insert
    overlap in the middle, and can be aligned to produce a longer, more accurate
    composite read, extending the scope of applications for high throughput
    shortread sequencing. A single lane of Illumina can be processed to generate
    upwards of 10 million ~200bp reads, allowing a deep look at complex
    metagenomic samples. The algorithm is generally applicable to any short read
    technology generating matepaired reads, and is open source.<br/>

    SHE-RA was used to process Illumina Genome Analyzer II reads for metagenomic analysis in this paper:
    <a href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0011840">
    Rodrigue S*, Materna AC*, Timberlake SC, Blackburn MC,
    Malmstrom RR, et al. (2010) Unlocking Short Read Sequencing for
    Metagenomics. PLoS ONE 5(7): e11840. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0011840</a><p/>
    <br/>
    SHE-RA package was written by Sonia Timberlake, with inspiration from Sebastien
    Roderigue, Arne Materna and Eric Alm. Website maintained by Sonia Timberlake
    with many thanks to Albert Wang. <br/>
    </div>

    <p/><hr></hr><p/>

    <h5>Downloads + Documentation Page</h5>
    <div id="softwareMed">
    <a href="shera/SHERA_doc4website_suppmethods.pdf">Documentation (pdf)</a><br/>
    <a href="shera/fraction_reads_ovl_s7.pdf">Yield: how it varies by length (in v1.0)</a><br/>
    All SHE-RA source code and example input files (Perl and *sh in tar.gz) can be downloaded <a href="shera/SHERA_files.tar.gz">here</a>.<br/>
    </div>

    <h5>NOTE ON NEW ILLUMINA HEADERS: </h5>
    <div id="softwareMed">
    Here's a patch to deal with them.<br/>
    Edit concatReads.pl.<br/>
    Replace this line (line ~140): check_seqNames($name1,$name2) or die "reads seem mislabeled";<br/>
    with this new code: map { s/ /:/g }($name1, $name2);<p/>
    </div>

    <h5>FAQ</h5>
    <div id="softwareMed">
    0.) I'm confused. Where do I start? <br/>
    Check out the readme file, and see
    our PlosOne paper, "Unlocking Illumina for Metagenomics," and the
    documentation section on this website.<p/>

    1.) Why do you need the adapter sequences? Aren't they already trimmed from
    the files? <br/>
    If an insert is shorter than your read length, the
    sequencing reactions "read" into the adapters. To capture these alignments,
    I include the adapter sequences.<p/>

    2.) You're doing an ungapped alignment. But what about indels in the reads?
    <br/>
    On the Illumina platform they are quite rare, so in this first version
    of this software I stuck with an ungapped alignment. Practically speaking,
    an indel in the putatively overlapping region will give you a poor alignment
    score, and a misalignment with low confidence score will be reported.<p/>

    3.) What's the deal with misalignments? <br/>
    Finding the best alignment for a short fragment of relative high error-rate
    sequence is not trivial, so misalignments are definitely something to think
    about! SHE-RA returns the composite read constructed from the best alignment
    of ALL sequences (preserving the input order), gives you a confidence score,
    and allows you to filter as you like. Your filtering approach should be
    based on your data, your downstream applications and your amount of free
    time. I provided a little script filterReads.pl as part of the download, and
    i think the threshold value 0.5 is a decent starting point to limit your
    misalignments, but this will vary with your dataset. I suggest shuffling
    your mate pairs and running SHE-RA to get a distribution of confidence
    scores for mis-alignments.<p/>

    4.) What does the program do if the reads don't actually overlap, ie if the
    insert length is longer than 2*read_length ? <br/>
    There's no way to know this, except in a probabilistic sense. The program
    outputs the best alignment for each read pair, with a confidence metric.
    Sequences from this scenario will largely be reported with the mates
    (erroneously) joined with a short (ie 10-14bp) overlap, and with low
    alignment confidence, which will allow you to filter them out as you choose.<p/>

    5.) From the example shell script, it looks the program might need a "base
    frequency file" - what is this, and how does it affect the data processing? <br/>
    This is an option i included for calculating the new quality scores in genomes
    with very high GC content. At present, it only effects the quality score, and
    not that much. In theory it should improve the approximation of error
    probability but I haven't tested whether it does in practice.<p/>
    </div>

    </midPane>
    <footer>

    </footer>
</Document>




