<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
    <Title>Alm Lab Member: Xiaofang Jiang </Title>

    <contentPane>
    <h3>Xiaofang Jiang</h3>
        <div id="member">
            <!-- rename the image file here. jpgs, pngs, whatever are fine. -->
        <img class="floatRight" src="img/xiaofang_jiang1.jpg" width="150" alt=""/>
        <h4>Research Interests</h4>
            To adapt their physiology to gradual and sudden changes occurring in the host environment or during inter-individual transmissions, commensals exhibit remarkable genetic variation diversity at a population level. I am interested in the genetic variations of gut microbes and how the variations are beneficial for  their effective colonization and successful survival. I am developing tools and mining genetic variations from isolate genomes and metagenomic data.
            <ul>
                <li>Single nucleotide variation</li>
                I am working with long-dense longitudinal metagenomic data to identify the SNVs that differentiated strains of same species to track strain-levels dynamics in microbiome.
                <li>Genomic rearrangement</li>
                I am particularly interested in DNA inversion and how these inversions generate hybrid proteins, shuffling domains between genes and rearranging operon structure.
                <li>Mobile genetic elements</li>
                I developed a Split Read Insertion Detection (SRID) method to detect mobile genetic elements in the microbiome and created <a href="https://immedb.mit.edu/" target="Intestinal microbiome mobile element">ImmeDB</a>, a database dedicated to the collection, classification, and annotation of mobile genetic elements (MGEs) from gut microbiome.
            </ul>
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/xiaofang_jiang2.jpg" width="150" alt=""/>
        <p/>
	</div>
    </contentPane>

    <rightPane>
        <br/>
        <div id="memberDir">
        <h4>Xiaofang Jiang</h4>
        Postdoctoral Associate<br/>
        xiaofang@mit.edu<br/>
        <p/>

        <h4>Education</h4>
        <ul>
        <li>PhD, 2016, Bioinformatics, Virginia Tech </li>
        </ul>
        <p/>
        <img class="floatRight" src="img/xiaofang_jiang3.jpg" width="150" alt=""/>
        </div>
    </rightPane>
        <!-- Don't change anything below here! -->
    <midPane>
    </midPane>
    <footer>
        <hr />
        <img src="img/bar1.png" alt="bar1"/>
    </footer>
</Document>
