<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
    <Title>Alm Lab Members</Title>

    <contentPane>
        <h3>Lab Members</h3>
    <h4>PI: Eric Alm</h4>
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatRight" src="img/ericAlm.png" width="150" alt="ericAlm"/>
        Research in my group includes both computational/theoretical
        and experimental approaches to understanding the evolution of microorganisms, emphasizing a
        'systems-level' perspective. Some areas of special interest include:
        <ul class="square">
        <li>Tools for detecting natural selection in microbes</li>
        <li>The evolutionary origin of gene families</li>
        <li>Mining metagenomic sequence data</li>
        <li>Experimental evolution of microbes</li>
        <li>Modeling bacterial ecology</li>
        <li>Gene regulatory networks in bacteria</li>
        <li>Protein structure and design</li>    
        </ul>
        <a href="ealm.html">Read more...</a>
    </div>
    <hr />
    <h4>Postdocs</h4>
    
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/6_Sean_Clarke.jpeg" width="150" alt="seanClarke"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Sean Clarke</font><br/>
        I use experimental evolution and whole genome resequencing 
        to study how bacteria adapt to high salinity in the lab and the 
        role of hypermutation in that process. I'm interested in how 
        microbes affect our everyday environments and our food.
        <a href="saclarke.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
   
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/corzett2.jpg" width="150" alt="mBansal"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Christopher Corzett</font><br/>
        I am interested in how microbes survive and thrive in diverse and dynamic
    environments. This includes understanding how bacteria sense and respond to
    environmental change, the metabolic machinery required for different feeding
    strategies, and how microbes adapt and evolve various lifestyles..... <a href="corzett.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
   
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/12_Greg_Fournier.jpeg" width="150" alt="gregFournier"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Greg Fournier</font><br/>
        My current research focuses on integrating phylogenetics and horizontal
        gene transfer (HGT) with studies of microbial evolution and planetary
        history. ... <a href="GFournier.html">Read more</a><p/><p/><br/>
    </div>
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/groussin1.jpg" width="150" alt="mathieu"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Mathieu Groussin</font><br/>
        Broadly speaking, I am interested in the inference of biological 
        properties of ancient prokaryotic life and in how bacterial and archaeal 
        communities evolve. My main interests focus on the study of genetic data 
        (DNA, proteins) to understand the main evolutionary processes...  <a href="mathieu_groussin.html">Read more</a>
    </div>  
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/29_Aliso.jpeg" width="150" alt="sarahPreheim"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Sarah Pacocha Preheim</font><br/>
        I am interested in bacterial diversity, especially within aquatic ecosystems.
        The small size, genetic diversity and metabolic versatility of bacteria make them
        ideal systems for studying principles in ecology and evolution... <a href="sPreheim.html">Read more</a>
       

    </div>
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/12_Manu_Tamminen.jpeg" width="150" alt="manuTamminen"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Manu Tamminen</font><br/>
        I'm investigating novel approaches to extract and analyze genomic and transcriptomic
        information from single cells. To achieve this exciting objective I use a variety of
        tools, including flow assisted cell sorting, microfluidics, molecular biology and
        computational analysis. This combination of laboratory and computational approaches
        has considerable benefits over metagenomics... <a href="mvtammin.html">Read more</a>

    </div>
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/avihu2.jpg" width="150" alt="avihu"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Avihu Yona</font><br/>
        During my doctoral research I utilized experimental evolution to study
        the evolutionary dynamics of genomic duplications like aneuploidy and
        tRNA genes. Now, I’m interested in the way complex communities evolve as
        an integral entity and in how evolutionary forces can be applied to
        reshape such communities towards desirable traits... <a href="avihuYona.html">Read more</a>
    </div>  
     <hr/>
    <h4>Staff</h4>
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/antolik1.jpg" width="150" alt="seanClarke"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Caroline Antolik</font><br/>
        As Technical Assistant in the Alm lab, I help out with various
        aspects of lab members' projects. My main responsibilities include 16S
        library prep for Illumina sequencing and training for users on
        specialized equipment such as our Bioanalyzer and liquid handling robot... <a href="antolik.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
    <hr/>
    
    <h4>Graduate Students</h4>
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/SeanPhoto1.jpg" width="150" alt="seanKearny"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Sean Kearney</font><br/>
        Microbes rule the world; our very existence is dependent on the once
        free-living oxygen-respiring bacteria now known as mitochondria. We
        cannot even begin to imagine how interlocked our own lives are with
        those of 4000 million year old organisms. I am interested in studying
        how microorganisms influence evolution and ecology over vast temporal
        and spatial scales.... <a href="skearney.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
     
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/scotto_3.png" width="150" alt="scott"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Scott Olesen</font><br/>
        Microbial metabolisms transform the world around us, mediating key
        geochemical cycles and even determining human scent. I combine
        experimental design and computational techniques to assess and engineer
        the role of microbes in the environment and the human microbiome...<a href="scott_olesen.html">Read more</a> 
    </div>
    
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/12_Allison_Perrota.jpeg" width="150" alt="allison"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Allison Perrotta</font><br/>
        My current focus in the lab is to create and test high throughput
        methods for preparing 16s Illumina sequencing libraries from diverse
        environmental sources. Our lab researches the microbial ecology found in
        a myriad of environments and under diverse conditions... <a href="aperrott.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
    
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/shapeimage_4-1.png" width="150" alt="smillie"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Chris Smillie</font><br/>
        I'm interested in using computational methods to study the evolution and
        ecology of the human microbiome. Previously, I've collaborated with
        Sarah, Eli, and Paco to develop SLiME, a tool that uses machine learning
        to identify microbial signatures associated with disease... <a href="csmillie.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
    
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/1_Mark_Smith.jpeg" width="150" alt="smith"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Mark Smith</font><br/>
        Broadly, I am interested in understanding the many ways that the hidden
        microbial majority influences the world around (and within) us.
        Currently, my research is focused on uncovering and characterizing a
        network of gene exchange in the human microbiome through comparative
        genomics... <a href="mbsmith.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
    
    <div id="member">
        <img class="floatLeft" src="img/sspencer1.jpg" width="150" alt="spencer"/>
        <font class="fontTitle">Sarah Spencer</font><br/>
        I'm interested in how ecological principles play out at the resolution
        of single cells. To explore this I'm developing high-throughput
        sequencing technology that can immobilize interacting cells for
        downstream 16S profiling. I'm starting to apply this technique to
        aquatic communities, but eventually I'd like to adapt the protocol to
        address other problems in microbial evolution and ecology.
        <a href="sspencer.html">Read more</a>
    </div>
    
    
    <br />
    <hr />
    </contentPane>
    
    <rightPane>
    <br/>
    Current Members
    <div id="memberDir">
    <ul>
    <li><a href="ealm.html" class="nodec">Eric Alm</a></li>
    <li><a href="antolik.html" class="nodec">Caroline Antolik</a></li>
    <li><a href="saclarke.html" class="nodec">Sean Clarke</a></li>
    
    <li><a href="corzett.html" class="nodec">Christopher Corzett</a></li>
    <li><a href="GFournier.html" class="nodec">Greg Fournier</a></li>
    <li><a href="mathieu_groussin.html" class="nodec">Mathieu Groussin</a></li>
    <li><a href="skearney.html" class="nodec">Sean Kearney</a></li>
    <li><a href="scott_olesen.html" class="nodec">Scott Olesen</a></li>
    <li><a href="aperrott.html" class="nodec">Allison Perrotta</a></li>
    <li><a href="sPreheim.html" class="nodec">Sarah Preheim</a></li>
    <li><a href="csmillie.html" class="nodec">Chris Smillie</a></li>
    <li><a href="mbsmith.html" class="nodec">Mark Smith</a></li>
    <li><a href="sspencer.html" class="nodec">Sarah Spencer</a></li>
    <li><a href="mvtammin.html" class="nodec">Manu Tamminen</a></li>
    <li><a href="avihuYona.html" class="nodec">Avihu Yona</a></li>

    </ul>
    </div>
    <br/>
    Former Members
    <div id="memberDir">
    <ul>
    <li><a href="http://www.engr.uconn.edu/~mukul/ " class="external">Mukul Bansal</a></li>    
    <li><a href="http://microfluidics.epfl.ch/twiki/bin/view/MaerklLab/LbncPeople" class="external">Matthew Blackburn</a></li>
    <li><a href="franciscocamas.html" class="nodec">Francisco Camas</a></li>
    <li>Jonathan Friedman</li>
    <li><a href="http://www.ladlab.org" class="external">Lawrence David</a></li>
    <li><a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/arnematerna" class="external">Arne Materna</a></li>
    <li><a href="elipapa.html" class="nodec">Eli Papa</a></li>
    <li><a href="http://www.shapirolab.ca/" class="external">B. Jesse Shapiro</a></li>
    
    <li><a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/sonia-timberlake/65/283/b13" class="external">Sonia Timberlake</a></li>
    </ul>
    </div>
         
    </rightPane>
    <midPane>
    
    </midPane>
   
    
    <footer>
       
    </footer>
</Document>
